hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft
actually let's see if i can do this in
third person
oh i don't like this i don't like this
at all
and whatever if i zoom in no no no no no
no no no
welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft now today the end of the war
has happened the hermitcraft feud is
officially concluded but we will get to
that a little later on in the episode
because
today i'm basically finishing this
entire base maybe okay maybe not the
inside but the outside is all complete
and i have put hours and hours and hours
of work into this so we're actually
gonna kick off today's episode with two
short time lapses so let's jump into
that and answer some of your questions
from twitter
first of all let me explain why i'm
removing an entire desert for my first
time lapse basically i plan on finishing
the base in the next time-lapse so i
need a lot of glass and i need a lot of
concrete so
my sand has depleted so this is what it
looks like in the background this is the
sort of thing that i have to do so i
thought i'd time-lapse it today anyway
the first question is by jasper who says
where is the tag game it was last with
good times with scar unfortunately he
got ill so it's kind of still with him
but we're not sure whether the tag game
should continue or not so we'd love your
opinions in the comments down below
whether we should continue the game or
not or just leave it or find a way of
finishing it off the next question is
from jacksonfelt who says just put a
picture of pearl and maui on screen you
got it chief look at this boom bap
that
is
my kittens and they are so so cute
actually they're not really kittens
anymore they're like two years old the
next question is from april may who says
are you ever going to do a live stream
again well i would absolutely love to
especially on hermitcraft because i've
not done one before and i'd love to see
how it goes live streaming on youtube
however i'm not a live streamer i'm a
video maker predominantly so doing a
live stream is a little bit out of my
comfort zone but i'd love to give it a
try and maybe i could let you guys know
when i plan on doing it and we could see
how that all goes and my favorite food
is definitely sticky toffee pudding
i've got a bit of a bad sweet tooth
the next question is from josh who says
what was your dream job as a kid before
doing youtube well when i was growing up
um perhaps a little older than a lot of
you uh youtube didn't really exist
especially when i was really young it
didn't come around until i was a sort of
a teenager so youtube wasn't even a job
that you could do i didn't really know
what i wanted to do at school and if you
ask me now i honestly don't really know
but i love game design and i love making
videos so probably something creative
like that the last question is from
victor who says have you ever been
bullied for playing minecraft because i
know i have hey it's okay to play
minecraft and if you ask people if they
play minecraft as well and then they
take the mick that's
just sort of the person you don't want
to talk to so try not to worry about it
too much
obviously when i tell people that i play
minecraft on youtube sometimes they
don't understand and that's okay because
they probably never played the game and
don't realize how amazing this game is
so i feel a little bit sorry for them
so i basically had to gather a bunch of
sand to be able to make this and then i
went and finished the outside of the
base and my goodness does it look
finalized
finally
from the outside it looks like this it's
nice not having the floating ring i
wondered about keeping it floating for a
really really long time but i kind of
like the fact that it's got a big base
now apart from the interior this whole
thing
is now complete i went ahead and fixed
up anything that was
uh powder in there and i even added the
details on the back so these little
lines here and down at the bottom
and i even finished off some of the
terracotta detailing around this base
underwater all the stuff that you don't
really normally see
but it had to be done anyway to get the
whole thing looking oh maybe i didn't
finish maybe i only did it on one side
it was a very long day building i think
i took about 12 hours in total well
anyway i'm super happy that this can be
called relatively finished because i am
now starting to work on my new project
and it's not really my new project it's
an architect project so that's right me
and mumbo have decided that we're going
to be working on building up architects
bigger and better than ever before we
didn't really do much before we mainly
messed around but we feel that now after
the war is finished
we can go ahead and do more with
architects because there's a lot of
potential there and there needs to be
diamonds made because we've spent all
the money that jeffen paid us to remove
his mustache
and you might be wondering what i'm
doing here i actually want to create a
weird potato farm tube because i
actually have started running out of
potatoes you remember really back early
on in the series there was i had my
potato farm well yeah that's that's all
dried up now so i need to automate it
and there's a pretty cool design out
there so i'm gonna try my best to fit it
in this tube i definitely didn't come up
with this idea by the way i'm totally
i'm totally stealing iskall's farm
design but i just need to make it work
for my little area here so i'm gonna
make one layer
so basically i'm gonna have to create
many many layers for this farm now green
does technical is not really a thing i'm
completely talking rubbish most of this
by the way i'm just copying a farm but
mumbo actually
sat in a cool with me and explained how
it works so i genuinely i genuinely
understand how this farm is going to
work
and i hope that it looks really cool in
this rather unfinished tube so let's
just do one layer and yes i'm not gonna
have any villagers to put in this to
begin with but hopefully we'll get the
idea and then i can finish the rest of
this off camera
so the layers are really as simple as
this i've put the first one together and
i think this is this is if it was any
more complicated than this i really
wouldn't understand now the key part of
this whole thing isn't here because what
we really need is some farming villagers
but i'm going to ask mumbo to send some
over in whatever way he sees fit so
basically
the farmers go ahead and they they go
and make my potatoes for me now what
they do is
this place here will be too dark for
potatoes to grow in
so what this does is it updates it so
the villager the poor little guy he
comes over he tries farming with this he
tries placing down the potatoes and
because this is updating and it's too
dark it just pops off every single one
he makes so he goes around he collects
them all and he basically keeps trying
to plant here but because it's too dark
it fails it then falls through
into the hopper system down here and
basically we make loads of loads of
layers of this all the way up to the top
and there we have a farm so this is
going to take a little bit of redstoning
and i definitely need to make sure that
those light levels are working correctly
because that's the bit that's probably
not going to work out for me but imagine
potato tube all the way to the top and
in fact that's definitely what i'm going
to work on next because this is fairly
simple it takes a couple of observers
and i've even got a little system
to send items all the way down through
all of the layers with minimal
redstoning possible so this should be
really really cool
anyway i think that's more than enough
base talk for now we've done
the outside of the base for good it is
complete we've got a few more layers to
fix inside here but i'm sure all of you
have been waiting to see what happened
with the hermitcraft civil war well
that's what we're going to do right now
so we're going to go back in time a
little bit and see how all of that
played out just to clarify a few things
before you see the end of the fight you
are not allowed to use your elytra and
we are not allowed to use anything over
iron armor you are allowed to use
whatever potions that you like and you
are allowed to kill the opposition's
mobs that they've got other than that
there's not really any rules so to speak
so i don't really want to see any
comments getting really upset about the
rules because the end result has been
finalized and we all agree that it was
how it worked out so let's see how this
all played out and who won the war
[Music]
okay guys
are we ready
if you press tab you'll see that there's
a lot of people
means the final battle is on i hope that
we're all prepared for what's to come
yes we shall be going down into their
base
and up in the rankings oh my gosh
scrap the war this is all we're doing
for the rest of the day
this is it g team sorry about that
i just want to mention now that this is
going down like we are on eight lives
and they are on 10 guys so
we're a little bit behind yeah yeah so
they've but we have one more person as
well so we there it's kind of even if
you ask me like we've got one more
person they've got two more lives
i think i'd probably have
[Laughter]
we just need to wait for both teams to
signal and then
well they are ready they're ready i'm
gonna type ready now
good luck g team good luck everyone's
get their flag we've got this goodly
team ready i'm suddenly not sure
[Laughter]
please please
seriously mumbo put the weather skull
back on we don't want to see that
i do
but when you have facial hair but not
your face
okay that's fine that's fair enough
don't worry no matter how this war goes
whether you win or lose you'll get your
mustache back
that is that yeah that's fantastic and
that's a win for the whole server if you
ask me i'm gonna
mean whatever happens
yeah
both teams are ready we're just waiting
for our uh very good that's what we're
waiting for okay okay all right jeff you
with me
absolutely sir let's do this thing
there's some cobblestone in one of these
chests yeah here we go what do you want
cold stone for oh we got that who's that
just yeah just
left the building
okay right
limber up no no wait wait jevin before
we go to battle look at me in the eye
look at me dead in the eye right squat
squat and squat we need to limber up you
can't go in without stretching
okay breathe it out breathe out no
sticky keys
oh oh god
okay i need i got one more for you i got
one more for you right yeah yeah yeah we
stretch we stretch
we're compressing we gotta extend
extend
extend okay
okay cool yeah there we go
some potions and kill these fools so
concorpo up there they're going to be
commentating on everything i believe
this is an official
end to the war all right
i see i see a false i see them over at
there
you're not gonna hit me for are they
seriously gonna try and hit me from
there oh yeah you've got a forward thing
here hold on
i'm going for it
oh this is gonna be great are they are
they shooting fireballs they're shooting
arrows but they're not going to hit us
and i'm going to make some walls over
here so they can't get through wolves
don't win wars jevin
i think they help us now get shot in the
face i did oh who blew up
oh cleo clear's lost her life already oh
my god poor cleo um i did actually pay
concorp i think this is the weapon that
i purchased i'm not really sure i'm
gonna give it a go i don't what is it
has it done anything
yeah oh it lagged yeah yeah okay so lag
is our weapon apparently because that
did nothing
we're actually taking a lot of fire here
we need we need to distract
these guys to so that joe can make a
a bridge over their moat because that
moat is actually deadly it was actually
my bad because i got loads of guardians
there um but uh we just need to get
across their moat to get to the flag i'm
like oh my god there's so much
do they know i'm here
hold on buddy i'm just gonna
do my thing
and oh yeah i saw your particles
hey i'm down here guys i'm down here
look at me
come and shoot at me
are you okay i've blown a wall
i'm stuck in the water okay this was a
terrible idea i'm just i'm a sitting
duck literally quack rack
[Laughter]
[Music]
oh
was that was that the tnt by any chance
that was the tnt i fell into the hole
dude they've got so many people like
we're two against them at least they're
not looks like we got a successful
bridge we've got a successful bridge oh
yeah as long as we keep that intact
we'll be able to get to the flag
oh hey i hit wells um ren and ren's like
oh he's like getting a llama or
something i just i can't believe what
i'm seeing i'm gonna run over real fast
and just break some blocks and i'm just
gonna keep picking at it
okay
uh careful false false is there dude
boss is there dude false is that she's
going to kill you don't touch me
save me
get out get it get her yeah
uh jevin
yes back it back at g-team base
there's like
uh a million oh my
god oh my god i've seen them i said
everywhere there's witches and
charged creepers and not good not good
i mean i shouldn't be laughing because
we just lost the life but they've read
they renamed the creeper oopsie
oh my god
uh oh okay star nine g5 wow we gotta
start getting some kills yes we
definitely need to start getting some
kills but it's so difficult when they're
up there like that not possible that
false is that dude where are you
where's she at i hit her i hit her i hit
her uh we need a change of attack we're
not gonna get any kills like this we're
gonna run out of lives before we can
even get to the flag
yeah it's this is we gotta we gotta
think of a better plan here clear we're
going to try and get a kill here hold on
yeah well he's getting gang up on wells
going up on wells i've only got stone
swords it doesn't matter keep going no
don't let him don't let him get away get
him
i'm trying
my arrows are like not he's in the boat
he's in the boat
you guys keep them busy like literally
you need to get their fire and i'm gonna
sneak in okay i'm gonna go straight to
the flag since we're really running out
of lives good luck all right i have an
invisibility potion so if i take
everything off and have nothing in my
hands
that including potatoes
you cannot see me and i'm gonna run i'm
gonna walk straight in there and i'm
going to find the flag
if i can get past hopefully with it's
nice and dark they won't see the
particles
oh this is not good hold on i might be
able to make it across
okay i am in star team seven lives i'm
gonna close the door
oh i forgot about this part
no one's in here with me
okay right
so i need to find my way
into is there a flag in there
no there's so many rooms in here with
nothing in a cave and
a cave and a spider can mobs see me when
i'm invisible right let's get regen in
here anything in here nope just you
little zombit uh
empty
empty come on where is it this is
ridiculous no creepers nope nope oh my
goodness where is it i have limited time
in here uh
there there's a flag there's a flag nope
just a creeper
that looks like uh ow that looks like
it's done well i'm not going here not
going in there
this room
no just a cave again
i've been through so many caves
no nothing again
i've literally been on almost every
single one no that does not even dude
there's not even a cave in this one no
yeah wait that's something and it hasn't
been opened yet is there something in
here this is this is this is sending me
all the wrong vibes everybody i know
that there's a war going on above me but
there it is there's the flag hold on i i
better eat for this in case i need to
run
wait
uh-oh
uh
i don't know what
okay okay
oh
um
okay okay okay okay go for the
[Laughter]
i thought i was definitely gone i didn't
think that oh of course they can't blow
up the puff fish okay can i just run for
it now
yeah do i have to stay here again
no we're okay go
go go go go go go go go go now i've just
got to find my way out and get back to
the gt base i mean to be honest with you
the labyrinth has defeated me more than
any of these fake rooms
i am so lost
no wrong way i've got the flag i've got
the flag i've got the flag and now i
have to hold it i have to keep it in my
hand if i'm the flag bearer that's kind
of just you know gentlemen's rules don't
you think i'm still invisible nothing on
me
[Music]
go go go go go go go go go go go go go
go go go
i'm making a run for it okay avoid the
mobs now i have to be so careful because
seriously i have no i have no armor
i have nothing uh job job job i came
around i better get back onto the
battlefield at least to be fair yeah
there's traps here so it's safe
am i going to make it ren got saying i
need to get back before all of the lives
run out that's the main thing wait can
they even see me i don't think
the mobs can see me when i'm invisible
have i been panicking for nothing
stupid witch no okay now he can see me
no wait i've got iron bars
okay quickly
run to the base
false was slain by iscow
exuber oh there's not enough time i've
got the banner i got the banner i'm
going in i'm going again does this mean
we win i better get it okay let's play
it fair let's get it to all the other
ones we're almost there
flag captured flag
captured did we run out of lives
we might have just lost the last life
as the flag has been captured
it's that's it we we win unbelievable
yes
it's not so fun celebrating alone
have you seen what concorpo doing right
now they've just disappeared on like a
floating machine
these guys are peacing out what's going
on
um guys
gg gg
the incredible strategy of using ijevan
as a distraction that drew the three of
us from the front of the base that great
i used an invisibility potion to walk
straight past everybody uh
something just happened
that's literally the oldest trick in the
book this was seriously cool and i want
to thank every single person for an
awesome awesome fight it was really cool
and friends again let's promise never to
fight again until next season
[Laughter]
thank you promise
no hard feelings let's get back to our
normal um who yeah one question before
we all go back to our normal lives and
be friends again
who's cleaning up
um
yeah i'm out guys yeah
so that's it the hermitcraft civil war
has officially come to an end and g-team
took the win but to be honest with you
if you haven't already seen it
the teen star guys they released this
diss track on us like they made a rap
song and it's
absolutely fantastic i was you know i
was clutching my chest i was like oh uh
i was
devastated guys so despite us winning in
the final battle
i think team star really did
fight the good fight and they they won
the rap battle that's for sure
we didn't even get to do a response in
the end because they absolutely
devastated us just in time for this war
it was it was phenomenal i can't i can't
praise it enough a lot of time and
effort went into it i'll link it down
below so you guys can check it out and i
had a lot of fun with this war but i
think it's definitely time for it to end
i don't even really remember
why we why we started this whole thing i
honestly oh yeah there was a bunch of
pranks and stuff
you know
in hindsight
it really didn't matter it really didn't
matter too much about the pranks
it all just went spiraling out of
control well i'm glad that we can start
going back to our normal lives
or maybe
we go back to our secret lives
hmm
i hope you've enjoyed the civil war and
i think that's probably the last episode
of the hermitcraft civil war for the
rest of the season it's been a fantastic
little project to be working on and i'm
so proud of everybody that got involved
with it because this this is insane this
is absolutely insane
anyway thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you've enjoyed this
episode of hermitcraft and in the next
one we shall be getting into the
architects project i hope you're all
excited for it let me know all of your
thoughts and feelings down in the
comments below as usual and good bye